<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ibrahim Abou Elenein</title>
    <link>https://aboueleyes.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ibrahim Abou Elenein</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 23:57:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aboueleyes.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vim Find and Replace</title>
      <link>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/vim-find-and-replace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 23:57:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/vim-find-and-replace/</guid>
      <description>![vim.png]
Basic search and replace In Vim, you can find and replace text using the :substitute (:s) command.
To run commands in Vim, you must be in normal mode, the default mode when starting the editor. To go back to normal mode from any other mode, just press the ‘Esc’ key.
The general form of the substitute command is as follows:
:[range]s/{pattern}/{string}/[flags] [count]The command searches each line in [range] for a {pattern}, and replaces it with a {string}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Sessions</title>
      <link>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/vim-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:41:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/vim-sessions/</guid>
      <description>Vim is an awesome editor. Vim provides a tool to save your time, helping you to get back to the previous mindset of the last time you left the project. It’s called sessions.
 A Session keeps the Views for all windows, plus the global settings. You can save a Session and when you restore it later the window layout looks the same. You can use a Session to quickly switch between different projects, automatically loading the files you were last working on in that project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Vim Setup</title>
      <link>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/my-vim-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:13:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/my-vim-setup/</guid>
      <description>Writing English words and writing code are very different activities. When programming, you spend more time switching files, reading, navigating, and editing code compared to writing a long stream. It makes sense that there are different types of programs for writing English words versus code
As programmers, we spend most of our time editing code, so it’s worth investing time mastering an editor that fits your needs.
Vim has a rich history; it originated from the Vi editor (1976), and it’s still being developed today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Easiest Way Ever to Make Nice Presentaions</title>
      <link>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/the-easiest-way-ever-to-make-nice-presentaions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 19:57:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/the-easiest-way-ever-to-make-nice-presentaions/</guid>
      <description>As a Linux user, we really love doing things from the terminal, we love to code, we hate GUI, We have no time to drag and drop as “muggles”
 I care about the technology. There are people who care about the user interface (UI); I can’t do UI to save my life. I mean if I was stranded on an island and the only way to get off that island was to make a pretty UI, I’d die there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Started Blogging</title>
      <link>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/why-i-started-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 23:13:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/why-i-started-blogging/</guid>
      <description>I would like to motivate my friends to blog, I will explain why.
Documentation as a Way of Studying. One of the best ways to digest what you learn is to be able to articulate what you learned in your words and come up with takeaways. So, write a tutorial blog post or anything that will help you understand in-depth what you are learning and know it by heart.
 If You Really Want to Master Something, Teach It The person who learns the most in any classroom is the teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
