<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Ibrahim Abou Elenein</title>
        <link>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Ibrahim Abou Elenein</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 19:57:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>The Easiest Way Ever to Make Nice Presentaions</title>
            <link>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/the-easiest-way-ever-to-make-nice-presentaions/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 19:57:50 +0200</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/the-easiest-way-ever-to-make-nice-presentaions/</guid>
            <description>As a Linux user, we really love doing things from the terminal, we love to code, we hate GUI, We have no time to drag and drop as “muggles”
 I care about the technology. There are people who care about the user interface (UI); I can’t do UI to save my life. I mean if I was stranded on an island and the only way to get off that island was to make a pretty UI, I’d die there.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/image.png" alt=""></p>
<p>As a <code>Linux</code> user, we really love doing things from the terminal, we love to code, we hate <code>GUI</code>, We have no time to drag and drop as <code>“muggles”</code></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I care about the technology. There are people who care about the user interface (UI); I can’t do UI to save my life. I mean if I was stranded on an island and the only way to get off that island was to make a pretty UI, I’d die there.
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted --><em>Linus Torvalds</em><!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Microsoft PowerPoint is really pain, specially if you are writing presentation that includes Math equations or code snippets</p>
<h2 id="latex">LaTeX</h2>
<p>So using latex <code>beamer</code> is much superior for many reasons :</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Consistent tools. I use LaTeX for my regular study. I need an easy way to get my &ldquo;printed&rdquo; work into the presentation. <code>LaTeX-beamer</code> allows me to do this very easily. All the way to publishing it on my homepage.
This in particular includes the various functionality ranging from formulas, code excerpts to any other <code>LaTeX</code> extension.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Focus. On the contents, not on the presentation. Once you are used to <code>LaTeX</code>presentations, <code>PowerPoint</code> pretty much looks like a drawing program to you, instead of a presentation tool.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Quality. Even with &ldquo;just&rdquo; screen resolution, <code>LaTeX</code> just looks more polished.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>As for being static. I never use animations in my presentations. They tend to distract people from what I&rsquo;m saying. And after all, it&rsquo;s not a slideshow, but a talk.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Programmable. You can even write programs to generate your slides. Or plots.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>But this may be too much for simple presentations</p>
<h2 id="markdown">Markdown</h2>
<p>We all know how cool <code>markdown</code> is, and it has  very easy syntax, so can we really make presentations with <code>markdown</code>? Let&rsquo;s do it!</p>
<p>First you should have <code>LaTeX</code> installed</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"> $ sudo apt install texlive-latex-recommended
</code></pre></div><p>Also download <code>pandoc</code></p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">$ sudo apt install pandoc
</code></pre></div><p>Now we are ready!</p>
<p>Open <code>vim</code> or your favorite text-editor and create the md file</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">$ mkdir pres 
$ cd pres 
$ vim pres.md 
</code></pre></div><p>And now write the following into the file</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">---
title:
<span style="color:#66d9ef">-</span> Ibrahim&#39;s pres 
author:
<span style="color:#66d9ef">-</span> Ibrahim Abou Elenein
theme:
<span style="color:#66d9ef">-</span> Copenhagen
---

# Section One 

Some Text 

+ item one 
+ item two 
+ etc ... 

# Section Two 

<span style="color:#75715e">## subsection 
</span><span style="color:#75715e"></span>BLA BLA BLA
</code></pre></div><p>Now run the following command</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">$ pandoc pres.md -t beamer -o pres.pdf 
</code></pre></div><p><img src="/img/src1.png" alt="">
<img src="/img/src2.png" alt="">
<img src="/img/src3.png" alt=""></p>
<p>Voilà!, here we have a very nice presentation, you can use all the features of <code>markdown</code>, The Sections are new slides.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Why I Started Blogging</title>
            <link>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/why-i-started-blogging/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 23:13:53 +0200</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://aboueleyes.github.io/posts/why-i-started-blogging/</guid>
            <description>I would like to motivate my friends to blog, I will explain why.
Documentation as a Way of Studying. One of the best ways to digest what you learn is to be able to articulate what you learned in your words and come up with takeaways. So, write a tutorial blog post or anything that will help you understand in-depth what you are learning and know it by heart.
 If You Really Want to Master Something, Teach It The person who learns the most in any classroom is the teacher.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I would like to motivate my friends to blog, I will explain why.</p>
<h2 id="documentation-as-a-way-of-studying">Documentation as a Way of Studying.</h2>
<p>One of the best ways to digest what you learn is to be able to articulate what you learned in your words and come up with takeaways. So, write a tutorial blog post or anything that will help you understand in-depth what you are learning and know it by heart.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If You Really Want to Master Something, Teach It
The person who learns the most in any classroom is the teacher.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="someone-is-searching-for-what-you-will-write">Someone Is Searching for What You Will Write.</h2>
<p>Don&rsquo;t hesitate to share your knowledge, you have something to share to the world!</p>
<p>As an undergraduate, you learn computer science fundamentals and many subjects in-depth. You learn data structures, algorithms, machine learning, computer architecture, databases, and many other computer fundamentals. Once you are a graduate, you have a job and start focusing on coding more.
You start to forget everything that you studied before, your learning curve is less as a graduate, and computer science always changes. So if you worked as a software developer, you may forget those operating system classes about scheduling techniques, even though they may help you to enhance your code. So even though what you learn as an undergraduate seems normal and well-known, graduates will enjoy reading and learning from what you write in on a daily basis.</p>
<h2 id="encourages-you-to-self-learn-more">Encourages You to Self-Learn More</h2>
<p>Once you start sharing your knowledge, get readers, you will be encouraged to learn more. Also, to be able to write better blog posts, you will always need to know a little more than what you study in university. Blogging educates you to read from others as well, so you will learn from others a lot.</p>
<h2 id="as-a-journal">As a Journal</h2>
<p>Last, studying anything takes a long time, and if you are in university it takes years! So, it is a great way to journal about your life as a student and see how you grew and learned more and more with time.</p>
<h2 id="improve-your-writing-skills">Improve Your Writing Skills</h2>
<p>One of the best ways to motivate yourself is to remember that you’re developing a skill that will serve you well for the rest of your life.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
